Never forget why you are the church.
So we're gonna go right back into digging into
eschatology, or, to put it simpler,
the study of the end times.
If you were, go ahead and turn your Bible to Revelation 13.
I'm gonna be kind of hitting a lot of scriptures pretty quickly.
And so that's why you have those notes, and if you ever need
the actual list of scriptures, if
the notes don't adequately do that for you.
You can just let me know that's an easy little send
for you, and I can get that to you.
But, um, again, so far, we have spoken
at great length about the tribulation, and more recently, the Antichrist.
Tonight, we are going to look at two questions that
can be derived from our text that we talked about two weeks ago.
Before we get to that particular text, however,
there are three end time players that we need to understand.
And so in Revelations 12 verse
9, you have what the Bible calls the Great Dragon,
which very obviously represents Satan.
It says this.
And the Great Dragon was cast out, that old serpent
called the devil, and Satan, which deceiveth the whole world, he
was cast out into the earth, and his angels were cast out with him.
Now, there is debate on whether this is something that has already happened.
This is something that is kind of happening right now, or
something that's going to happen later.
Here's what I can tell you.
We do know, according to Job, that
the devil is able to go to and
from, because remember, he went to God and said, Hey, have you considered your
servant Job, right?
And so we know that there is access there, okay?
So we also know that
the great dragon is going to have authority,
to some extent, on Earth, especially during
the great tribulation, he is now, seeking that,
which is, you know, that he can devour.
So, again, we're not gonna get too much into that, but
we do know that Satan is gonna have a big part in
the tribulation.
In Revelation 13.
We see two distinct beasts appear.
In verses one through 10, you have the beast from the sea.
This is the Antichrist, the one who comes in
great political authority, and power, the beast has 10
horns and seven heads.
Many believe that this is in connection
with the prophetic writing of Daniel, meaning that the Antichrist
will rule from what can be called the revived Roman Empire.
Now, this will consist of 10 kings and kingdoms
who will rule under the Antichrist at that time.
By the way, there is an interesting detail
found in the mention of the seven heads, if
you look at Revelation 13, verse one, and I stood
upon the sand of the sea, and saw a beast rise
up out of the sea, having seven heads and 10 horns, and
upon his horns 10 crowns, and upon his head the name, a blasphemy.
The reader in John's day would have had
little issue understanding and identifying
the meaning of this reference of the seven heads.
The Rome, the Roman Empire, was famously
known as the City of Seven Hills.
In other words, I believe that this further aids
the view of some form or somewhat
of a revived Roman empire that we see in the end times.
So, this beast for the sea is the antichrist,
but then we get to another beast.
Later in chapter 13.
And this is the beast from the earth.
And verses 11 through 12, and I beheld another beast coming
up out of the earth, and he had 2 horns like a lamb, and
he spake as a dragon.
And he exercised all the power, the 1st beast
before him, and caused it the
earth, and then was dwelled therein to worship the 1st
beast, whose deadly wound was healed.
The 2nd beast served as the
false prophet to the antichrist.
All right, so you have you have Satan, the great dragon.
You have the beast on the sea, which is the antichrist, and
you have the prophet, the false prophet of the antichrist, which is the beast from the earth.
Whereas the Antichrist is both political and religious
in nature, right, by the way, religion and
the area of worship is what dictates everything
in all life in all societies and cultures.
You do realize that.
Every culture, every society worships
something in someone.
And so we see that.
So, but the false prophet, the beast from the earth,
is more of a religiously fueled
entity trying to get everyone, or not
really trying, forcing everyone that will to worship the beast.
I like how pastor
name, or a book writer named Eckert explains this
seemingly complicated dynamic in his book, 40 Questions about the end times.
This is what he said.
This partnership shows the functional distinction.
We're talking about the different beasts.
The C beast, the Antichrist, wields
primary authority, while
the Earth beast, the false prophet, operates as its subordinate propagandist.
The false prophet working through the power of the dragon,
that Satan, heals the death poon of the beast,
as Satan parodies Jesus' passion, death, and resurrection.
Remember, this is all about antichrist against Christ.
It then get people to turn from the true Christ to the Antichrist,
that is the purpose here.
Now, there is a much needed reminder here.
Okay?
Before we get into the topic that we're supposed to talk about tonight.
There's a much needed reminder.
There will be a strong sense in the end times that Satan is winning.
It just will be.
When all the things going on, all things seeing, there's going to be a great delusion
given by God, and there's
going to be a lot of people that give in and give their
loyalty loyalty to the Antichrist.
But I want you to never forget that whatever power Satan wields
is permitted by God and God alone.
God allows Satan the power to fuel
and sustain these end time players in order to bring about
his good and perfect will.
By the way, I understand that a lot of things, if
you look at it from a secular view, if you look at it from a thing
of like, hold on, why does this even have to happen?
What is the purpose of the end times?
What is the purpose of all this?
What is the purpose of Israel rebelling and coming back and rebelling and coming back?
Because, listen, God's all sovereign.
He knew this from the beginning.
I want to give you an illustration here.
If you have children.
Before you had a child, okay,
did you know that that child would
hurt you, disappoint you, and potentially hurt themselves
in some way, form or fashion?
Did you know that?
Okay, well let me give you let me give
you some some parenting advice.
It's going to happen, right?
Amen.
Okay, thank you.
When my daughter sits there and I say, hey, baby, give me a hug.
And she says no, that disappoints me.
But anyway, either way, it can be more major things.
But what I'm trying to say is, we know that.
We know beyond a shadow of a doubt that that's going to happen.
Yet we still have them.
Why is that?
Because we want that relationship.
Right?
Now, that is a rough illustration because we're not perfect than God is.
We're not fully sovereign and God is.
Right?
But I want you to know when we look at this in the end
times, it's very easy to say, why in the world, why
couldn't God just wipe out Satan, forget all this?
Well, he has a plan.
And the Bible says that his way are higher
than our ways, right?
They're greater than our ways.
And so it's something good to think about.
So let's talk about what we're supposed to talk about tonight.
There's 2 things that live rent free in most believers'
minds when speaking of the end times, rent free, completely rent free.
And I've seen this.
It's all over social media.
It's all over podcast, world, it's everything.
And the 2 things are found in Revelation 13, verses 16 through 18.
Look at it.
It says this.
And he causes all the small and the great.
It's talking about the false prophet, and the rich
and the poor, and the free men, the slaves, to be given a mark
on their right hand or on their forehead.
You see, this is the mark of the beast.
And he provides that no one will be able to buy or
sell except the one who has the mark.
Either the name of the beast or the number of his name.
Well, what's the number?
Here is wisdom, verse 18.
Let him who has understanding, calculate the number of the beast, for
the number is that of a man, and his number is 666.
Two questions.
What does the mark of the beast and what does 666 mean?
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for this night.
I thank you for your word.
God, thank you for declarity that you do give us.
God, I thank you the faith that you give us to believe,
even when there's not the clarity that we desire.
So God, I pray you give us wisdom in the sermons tonight.
It's in Jesus name, you pray.
Amen.
Let's look at the 1st question here.
What is the mark of the beast?
Have you ever thought about that?
Have you ever speculated on that?
Everyone has, right?
Christians, non-Christians alike.
There is a as a matter of fact, a lot of popular
pastors right now on their social medias, they're talking about it.
And that's okay.
That word mark can be referenced in multiple verses in Revelation.
We see it in Revelation 14, verse nine,
verse 11, chapter 15, verse two, chapter 16, verse
two, chapter 19, verse 20, and chapter 20, verse 4.
In other words, it's all over the place.
Right?
That word mark in Revelation 13 is the Greek word taragma,
which literally means a mark, stamp, or a brand.
Other places where this word and
reference is used can also mean to mark for possession
for identity.
So we have a
plethora of meanings here.
We have a Mark Stamper brand.
And then we have a mark for possession or identity.
Therefore, this mark will identify
those who worship the image of the beast.
Now, There are some disagreements
on what the actual mark is.
Is it a physical mark put directly on a person's
forehead or right hand, or is it simply
a mark of faithfulness and loyalty to the Antichrist?
The 1st view is widely
accepted and deeply speculated that
it's a physical mark, a physical thing, a
tangible thing that is given and put upon us to buy and sell.
And it's a mark of the beast, the most obvious thought on this is a microchip.
Anyone ever heard the microchip argument, right?
Okay.
There is technology today that would make this easy to put in place, right?
As a matter of fact, it's not a microchip, but reports
came out recently, if you remember that the UK was going
to require digital IDs for everyone who resides there.
People immediately went full time,
uh, in time, full end time mode, and connected
this with the Mark of the Beast.
Interestingly enough, and this, I was actually looking this up today when
I was studying, because I'm thinking, I wonder where that's at.
I wonder, when that's happening, all the things.
I had a whole bunch of timelines that I was seeing.
But because of the backlash,
the intense backlash, they actually scrapped the idea.
So I just want to let you know, there is a little bit of common sense
still in the world, amen?
And so there are some issues, though, with this particular application.
First, if we connect every
little technological advancement to the mark of the beast,
we water down the reality of it.
In other words, it's not the mark of the beast
to get a medical chip or financial chip.
It's not the mark of the beast.
Does it seem sketchy to me?
Yeah.
Does when I personally get one implanted in my wrist?
Absolutely not.
Right?
But I don't believe that is the mark of the beast.
Now, now here's the thing.
Let's just think about something for a second.
Do you have a debit or credit card?
Raise your hand if you do.
Okay.
Well, let me ask you something.
Is that actual money?
It's not.
You should see my credit card from vacation.
It's weary, baby.
You know what I'm talking about?
But listen, no, but think about it.
Do you know how easy it would be for the
government just to freeze your car?
I don't think a
credit or debit card is the mark of the beast, though.
So there's technology in place that could resemble it.
But we don't have to fear things.
We don't have to necessarily fear, and I understand we can get into a really deep
route of AI and this and that and all the things.
And I understand that.
But I think it is very important to truly understand what
the market of the Beast is for and why it's even there, not
to try to think, oh, no, they came out with a Michaelchip, the end times are here.
First off, we should be waiting anyway.
We should be soberly,
steadfastly waiting for the Lord, regardless.
Oh, and by the way, for those that sit there and say,
well, I'm old school cash showing.
Listen, I'm a millennial.
ain't never got cash, okay?
Millennials don't, if you find I'm Leno that has cash, they got
an old soul, amen?
If I have cash, it's gone, son.
But here's the thing.
People say, well, you know, I do cash on.
Yeah, well, you know there's establishments right now that won't take cash.
And that's becoming more and more common.
Now, you notice that they're stopping making coins, right?
Like the pennies kind of, uh, uh, circulating out and and
they're going to try to that with a nickel.
It costs more than what it actually is worth to make.
And so before you know it, we are, I believe that we are gonna
go to a predominantly cashless society.
Right?
You can sit here and not like crypto all you want, but that's the,
that is the mode that we're going into.
And so what I'm trying to say is this.
All that could be right now, all that could be turned off in a moment.
to where you cannot buy or sell.
Y'all with me?
Doesn't mean it's the mark of the beast.
Okay?
This is not the market of beast, although it could
very well be paving the way for it.
Others think it's attached to our barcode.
Now, here's the thing.
I ain't got nothing much to say about that.
All that sounds interesting and listen, some of those could be true.
We have no idea.
Right?
But I want you to know what is most important to
realize, is who gets the mark and why?
Revelation 13, 15.
It was given to him to give breath to the image of the beast, so
that the image of the beast would even speak and cause as many as
do not worship the image of the beast to be killed.
We
see more description of this in Revelations 14, verse 9 through 11.
Then another angel, a 3rd one followed them and saying with a loud voice,
if anyone worships the beast in his image and
receives a mark on his forehead or on his hand, he
also will drink of the wine of the wrath of God, which is mixed in full strength
in the cup of his anger, and he will be tormented with fire
and brimstone in the presence of the holy angels in the presence of the lamb.
And the smoke of their torment goes up forever and ever.
And they have no rest day or day and night, those who worship
the beast in his image and whoever receives the mark.
Of his name.
And I have something here real quick.
That takes the doctrine of annihilation completely out.
Everyone know what I'm saying about that?
Okay, so there is a doctrine of annihilation that
teaches that there is no hell, that
when you die, you are completely annihilated, that is your punishment.
You just poof.
as if you never existed.
Well, well, Revelation 14 has something to say
about that in the smoke of their torment.
You can't torment something that doesn't exist.
The smoke of their torment
goes up forever and ever.
They have no rest.
They have no rest day and night.
So in other words, there's going to be time.
Forever and ever in torment.
Those who worship the beast in his image and
whoever whoever receives the mark of his name.
Do you see the do you see the critical importance here?
This mark directly identifies
those who worship the antichrist.
Therefore, we can only speculate
what the mark is because the beast is yet to be revealed.
This is actually a
strength of the view that the mark is simply
faithfulness to the antichrist.
Nothing would have to be added or speculated.
In other words, those who worship the beast are marked
by their allegiance to him.
I personally believe
there will be a physical marker of some kind, right?
I'm right there in the middle.
I don't think that it's just strictly allegiance.
A lot of people want to connect it to Nero and how
there was a covenant allegiance to the emperor in Rome.
And if you didn't, you were very, very easily identified
as someone who is not worshiping Caesar, therefore, you were taken care of, right?
I get what that, I get that mind process and things.
However, I do believe that there will be a mark, a stamp,
a brand of some kind, whether it be technology or not.
But here's the thing.
In this time, it
will not be possible to live in the middle ground.
America has
perfected the
imperfection in the tragedy of living spiritually in the middle ground.
By the way, that's why we
don't see the victory that we ought to as God's people.
There is
no longer going to be a fence.
By the way, there's no offense now.
People put up this make believe fence, right?
But there's no longer going to be that opportunity.
There is no like, well, on Sunday, I love Jesus, but on Monday
through Saturday, I'll just live like the world.
You don't get to do that anymore.
You got to make a decision.
Take the mark, worship the beast or not, worship Christ.
You hear me?
If we're going to worry about anything, we ought to worry about that now.
However,
those who refuse and lose their life because of it will be blessed and rewarded
according to Revelation 24, I love this.
Then I saw thrones, and they sat on them, and
judgment was given to them, and I saw the souls of those who had been beheaded
because of their testimony of Jesus, and because of the word of God,
and those who had not worshiped the beast or his image, and had not received the
mark on their forehead and on their hand, and they came to life and reigned
with Christ for a 1000 years.
It
is going to be worth resisting the mark in
the worship of the beast.
This further proves
there will be those in tribulation who remain faithful to Christ.
By the way, I want to say this, and I
got to be careful in this because I listen to so many resources
and podcasts and I read so many articles and studies and
the scripture and everything.
So there's a lot of things in my brain anytime we talk about this, because there's so much,
I can't hit everything.
But you do know there is one, there
is one religion who is known for
and has in their religion, a mode
of execution that is beheading.
There's one.
You know what that is?
Islam.
You do realize that.
What do we just read?
Hold on.
Those who have been beheaded because of the testimony of Jesus?
What I'm trying to say is,
we must be careful and we must stand up.
I'm not saying go to war, go to fight.
saying stand up and do what God has called us to do in our sphere
of influences because Islam is taken over fast
than we think, and I believe Islam is going to usher
in the Antichrist in the end times.
I do.
I believe it.
There's too much.
As a matter of fact, if you look at what their Messiah, who they're looking for to come,
their mighty, literally, if you read a description of
their Messiah and their promised one to come.
It is the exact description of our antichrist.
So
notice what's going on and realize that it all has the
Bible is living in right in front of us right now.
Amen.
So that's the mark of the beast.
This brings us to the next question.
What does 666.
I mean, what is the number of the beast?
Well, this one has brought just as much, if not more speculation, than the mark of the beast.
Now there is a particular study called
biblical numerology.
This study takes the numbers found
in the Bible and gives meaning to each one.
So there is there is a there's a
depth here.
So there's a number, and it means something,
and then there's also letters in the Hebrew language that
has a number attached to it.
All right?
So it kind of goes both ways here and people go crazy on
some biblical numerology.
For example, the most commonly repeated
numbers in the Bible is the number 7 and the number 40.
A 7 being God's number or the number of perfection
and completion and 40 being a number of probation and trial.
For example, God rested on which day?
The 7th day, right?
How many years were the Hebrews,
the Israelites in the wilderness?
40 years, 40 days and nights was nowhere in the art.
You see what I'm saying?
So there's and if you if you pay attention
to what's going on those 40 days, it's typically trial and probation.
How many days was Jesus in the wilderness fasting?
You see what I'm saying?
That was a trial on Jesus.
So we see that there are some legitimate
patterns of numbers in scripture.
There are many great resources for biblical numerology.
I am not teaching you that tonight.
That's not what this lesson's about, but you can go find out for yourself.
But this is where much of the speculation comes into play
with the number of the beast.
Again, look at Revelation 13, verse 18.
It says this, here is wisdom.
Let him who has understanding calculate
the number of the beast, for the number is that of a man, and his
number is 666.
Got questions.org has a great explanation of this.
Traditionally, 6 is thought to be the number of
man created on the 6th day and always falling short of God.
The beast Antichrist will strive to be like God.
He will even likely claim to be God.
But just as the number 6 fall short of number seven,
so will the beast, the Antichrist, for this trinity of
6 is ultimately fail in his effort to defeat God.
I want to remind you again,
God wins in the end.
We can talk about this.
It's all scary.
It's all all the things, but God wins.
Therefore, we win because we're with God.
Amen.
So who have people attach this number two?
Well, many people think Caesar Nero was
to be identified with 666.
As a matter of fact, the people that believe that the
mark is not necessarily a physical mark, but is a rather
an allegiance, an identifying allegiance to
the Antichrist, they bring Nero into play.
How do they get this?
How do they come up with this?
Well, they get this by taking each of the Hebrew letters
that make up his name, and add up the numbers associated
with them, and they get 666.
Others have actually identified Ronald
Reagan with this number.
Have you heard of that before?
Ronald Reagan.
They said, hey, he's identified?
I did not know this until I started studying.
Ronald Wilson Reagan.
Six letters in each name, right?
As a matter of fact, after his presidency, he moved to
a street in Bel Air called 666 Cloud Road.
Interestingly enough, he changed
the address to 668 because
there's so much conspiracy going around it.
You see how we can speculate?
By the way, Ronald Reagan is great of a president.
He's dead.
So in other words, we, I mean, he wasn't him.
Amen?
So I do believe that biblical numerology has its place.
But it is often taken, I believe, to
an extent that is above and beyond its intended meaning.
A smart person, hear me.
A smart person can make just about anything equal
to anything to mean anything, and they put enough time into it.
I can get up here and I can I can
put words together and say this is what this means.
That's what that means.
And it can sound really cool and really awesome, but it's it's
one of those things you really can't build a theology around it.
It's cool.
It's awesome when a preacher does it right, you're in awe, you know what I'm saying?
But we gotta be careful with it.
So instead of endless conspiracies.
Let's look yet again.
Revelation 13, verse 18.
Here is wisdom.
Let him who has understanding calculate the number of the beast, for
the number is that of a man and his number is 666.
John tells us that we'll be able to identify the beast
by the number, 6, 6, 6.
It's in the case that in the time where he
is revealed, it will be evident and openly known.
This is wisdom.
In other words, there won't be any more speculation.
There'll be, whoa, that right there, that's his number.
That's the beast.
Now, what does all this mean?
Well, regarding the number of the bees, it's best
to let things play out and allow God to make it evident and clearer than to speculate.
I've already told you, I don't believe I'm going to be here.
Right?
And if you believe that you're going to be here.
I hope you're wrong.
I hope I'm right.
Amen?
That's just as simple as that.
And I'm willing to change it midair, right?
I'm a midair eschatology kind of guy.
Like, if I'm up and we're going, it's like, well, we went through it.
Well, that stunk, but we're going to heaven.
Amen.
Like, we're gonna reign with Christ.
So either way, it's really not, it's fun.
It could be interesting.
It can be a cool little scripture, exercise,
but speculation can never be the foundation
for doctrine and theology.
That's when things get cultish.
Right?
When you take a speculation, right?
And say, well, this is what it is no matter what, then
before you know it, you start to twist scripture to prove your point.
And that's when you get into danger.
Okay?
If you ever if you ever hear a preacher say anything outside of Jesus
is the way, the truth, and life, that is, we know for a shadow of a down.
Jesus is the way, the truth, and the life.
We know that he came, lived, died, rose again.
We know that if you confess with your mouth, that Jesus is Lord, believe in your heart, that God arrest him.
then you will be saved.
Listen, we can know that.
I can stand up here constantly and say, that is truth
and nothing but the truth.
Amen.
However, if you start talking about these things that we really can't know all of it.
But you hear a preacher or a teacher say this is what
God is going to do.
Disregard that.
Spit out the seeds because I
don't care how smart he is.
He really doesn't know.
All right?
So just want to encourage you now.
So what about the mark of the beast then?
Instead of focusing on what the mark could be,
Right?
And getting all crazy every time we hear about a microchip or
a digital ID, whatever it is, right?
And instead of speculating on that, it is more important to
focus on what and who we worship today.
If we are so willing to worship
false idols in certain people today, what makes us think the masses
won't bend their knee immediately to the Antichrist Dan?
People are in
idol worship right now.
Here's the thing.
In America, we don't think of idol worship as we
think, well, no, not necessarily because we don't have idols set up in our homes,
like little figurines of now some people do, right?
Some people do, but in regards of like Old Testament
having like a wooden image or whatever, but I can tell you right now,
there's idols all up in our houses.
There's idols all up in our lives.
Right?
We hold an idol just about every single day and dedicate
our time and our passion.
That's the phone, right?
So we live in a culture that is full of idolatry.
It should not shock us.
When that time comes, that
the masses will give their allegiance and loyalty,
take the mark and worship the beast.
We
get so caught up in the things that we do not and really cannot know
while missing what is right in front of our faces.
The mark is associated with worship.
Those who worship
the beast are marked.
But you know what's beautiful about scripture, it tells us that
those who worship Christ are also marked.
It's not the mark of the beast,
but it's the mark of the Holy Spirit.
We are marked by God through
God for God.
So in other words, we are identified with Christ.
So the question is, who do you worship today?
This
is a marker of who you have given your life to.
Are you ready?
The question I ask every single time we talk about this.
If we're, if God was
to sound, to sound out trumpeter, if God was to call us up
in the air right now,
Are you ready?
If the anti- if the if
the covenant between the antichrist angel is made right now today
and we start seeing the signs in that way, are you ready?
If
later on, if we were in a time where he set up
and said, hey, you're going to worship me as God and the false prophet saying,
hey, you better worship him, you're going to take this mark or not, if
you don't take it, you're not going to buy, you're not going to sell, you're going to start a death.
Are you ready?
You know,
it's kind of like parenting.
Everyone knows how to parent until they start parenting.
You know what I'm saying?
I saw a video not too long ago about this
dude, he was, it was a video where he was looking almost like
into the past and the caption was seeing you
say the stupid things you said before you had kids.
And so he was like watching him and his
wife at a time before kids, say thing.
He was like, no, don't say it, right?
Because he knows that that's just going to be a bunch of garbage later, right?
They'll never sleep in our bed.
They'll never do this, right?
Our kid will never be that, right?
No, no, no.
What I'm trying to say is it's easy sitting here in
our comfort of American Christianity.
and say, man, you know what?
Bring it on.
But here's the thing.
What does our allegiance look like to Christ now?
What does our walk look like?
What does our prayer life look like?
How do we how do we
how do we love the word and studying it and digging into it?
All I'm trying to say is this, we better get prepared.
We better start strengthening our faith now.
So are you ready?
What Hezbanos goes out of this place?